<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on  </title>
    <link>/post.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Chuck Ha</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2013, Chuck Ha; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>2013-12-02 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using $GOPATH effectively.</title>
      <link>/post/gopath</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Chuck Ha</author>
      <guid>/post/gopath</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/code&gt; effectively can be confusing at first. If you follow guides on &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;golang.org&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll
end up with way too many packages and dependency confusion in &lt;code&gt;$HOME/go/src&lt;/code&gt;. This is the
exact same problem new Python developers have before someone tells them about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virtualenv.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;virtualenv&lt;/a&gt;. You end up
making a mess out of the system Python and use &lt;code&gt;sudo easy_install&lt;/code&gt; way too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we can ignore some of the fancy features that virtualenv provides. For instance, it
doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually make sense to have different versions for Go unless you&amp;rsquo;re working on the
language itself, in which case you probably know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. All we really care about
is having &lt;code&gt;go install&lt;/code&gt; put packages in the right place and not clobber or clutter anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all we are doing is modifying the environment to get a new Go workspace, I wrote a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chuckha/goenv&#34;&gt;simple bash script&lt;/a&gt; that does this for you. It creates the necessary directories for a Go
workspace (&lt;code&gt;pkg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt;), modifies the &lt;code&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt; variables and that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two versions, one spawns a subshell with these updated variables, found on the branch
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chuckha/goenv/tree/inve&#34;&gt;inve&lt;/a&gt; based on a gist about how &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/datagrok/2199506&#34;&gt;virtualenv is doing it wrong&lt;/a&gt; and one that I find a bit
more pleasant to use that you have to &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; and modify the current shell environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
